<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2023-04-16T22:41:21-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Portfolio</title><subtitle>Hi welcome to my portfolio website. Yopu can reach out to me on through my email or linkedIn</subtitle><author><name>Bhuwan Dutt</name></author><entry><title type="html">Analyse Public Opinion of Covid Vaccines</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/Project1/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Analyse Public Opinion of Covid Vaccines" /><published>2023-01-27T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-01-27T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/birthday</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Project1/">&lt;p&gt;I did this project back in March 2021. I had just started with my Masters in Computer Science program and because of the
pandemic the university was online. It was a grim time as India was battling with its second and the deadliest wave of Covid.
Vaccines had recently rolled out in India and most of us were still struggling to book an appointment. But there was a 
lot of uncertainties among public regarding the vaccines as there were at least 5 different vaccines that have 
been introduced in market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../media/giphy.gif&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During that time, I had just started exploring the field of NLP, and was eager to put my hands on it. So I thought why 
not use the NLP to analyse the sentiments of public regarding different vaccines. I had previous experience in web scraping 
and there is no better way to learn than to apply it to a real world problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, this was at the time when Large Language Models were unheard of, and every problem was being solved using some
kind of Neural Network, but because I wanted this to be an introduction to NLP, I went with the tradition ML based NLP.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;dataset&quot;&gt;DATASET&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First things first, to perform any kind of analysis, I needed the data. You can search online and find some good datasets
find some datasets, like this &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kaggle.com/datasets/gpreda/all-covid19-vaccines-tweets&quot;&gt;one&lt;/a&gt;.
But, public opinion can change over time, I couldn’t use an old dataset. So I decided to create my own dataset that has the most recent tweets.
And to solve my problem, I used the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tweepy.org&quot;&gt;Tweepy&lt;/a&gt;. Tweepy is a python library can filter tweets based on location, hashtags and language of tweets. This 
feature came in handy to extract tweet from a particular region or tweets about a particular vaccine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;data-preprocessing&quot;&gt;Data Preprocessing&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have ever seen a tweet, you will know that tweets are not in textbook format. Tweets generally contains abbreviations,
emojis, hashtags, shorthands, to keep things a little entertaining.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Bhuwan Dutt</name></author><summary type="html">I did this project back in March 2021. I had just started with my Masters in Computer Science program and because of the pandemic the university was online. It was a grim time as India was battling with its second and the deadliest wave of Covid. Vaccines had recently rolled out in India and most of us were still struggling to book an appointment. But there was a lot of uncertainties among public regarding the vaccines as there were at least 5 different vaccines that have been introduced in market.</summary></entry></feed>